Fernando J Soares



1000 Felipe Bender St Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil CEP 95660-000 +55 (51) 9 9918 7006 biofsdev@gmail.com

Self-taught I.T. hobbyist, cybersecurity undergraduate student, licensed Biologist

PROFILE

Data driven, science-oriented professional. Since 1986 I have been involved in information technology, teaching, learning and contributing to the field, especially where it intersects with science and biodiversity. For the past 13 years I have been the lead biologist at Tres Coroas townhall. During this time, I have developed my own company, and a few of my own projects: an online handbook APP for better practices in urban trees management, a system for implementing and monitoring public policies, a draft project for an environmental market platform, and a supporting platform for environmental consultants.

LANGUAGES	ENGLISH: ADVANCED		PORTUGUESE: NATIVE		SPANISH: INTERMEDIATE	
SKILLS	0		WEB DEV. SQL / POSTGRESQL DATABASE DESIGN DEPLOY	***	DATA COLLECTION DATA CLEANSING INFO SECURITY PROJECT MNG	****

RECENT **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2014 TO DATE - BUSINESS OWNER

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

QUADRAT ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANCY LTD. — as a small business owner and an environmental consultant since 2010 (when I returned to Brazil from 5.5 years stay in the USA), I do mostly environmental impact assessment studies and analysis of their respective technical documentations. My dream project for this company is to develop an environmental services marketplace platform where engineers, biologists, geologists and all highly qualified professionals can meet for support, expertise exchange and sales.

2012 TO DATE - LEAD BIOLOGIST

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

CITY TOWN HALL OF TRES COROAS — As Lead Biologist I have been working extensively with environmental licensing, biodiversity management and urban trees management, while coordinating socioenvironmental projects involving education and riparian forest restoration.

2005 - 2010 - RESEARCH ASSISTANT / ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

Melbourne, FL, USA

FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY — While pursuing my Ph.D., I have worked assisting research with data collection, data wrangling, data cleansing and data analysis for a mobile app to help Alzheimer's caretakers, and for a nationwide environmental education assessment project. I have also taught undergrad courses like University Experience and Survey of Science, while supporting the Women's Business Center with basic computer operations classes, mostly Windows OS and MS Office skills.

EDUCATION

1988 – 2002 UNIVERSITY OF THE SINOS RIVER VALLEY – UNISINOS

Sao Leopoldo, RS - Brazil

B. Sc. Biology (Graduate and Licensed Biologist)

Canoas, RS - Brazil

Master of Science Education for Sustainable Development

2005 - 2010 FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - FIT

Technologist in Information Security

2003 - 2005 LUTERAN UNIVERSITY OF BRAZIL - ULBRA

Melbourne, FL - USA

A.b.D. Environmental Education E.Ed. Interdisciplinary Studies

Tres Coroas, RS - Brazil

2024 - to date UNIASSELVI

SOCIAL



in linkedin.com/in/fsoares/



FORMER EXPERIENCE

From high school graduation as a Chemistry Technician, I moved on to the field of education and for half of my career, I was a high school and/or college teacher working in private and public schools. During this time, I also taught BASIC and LOGO programming languages.